Guide to the New Arts Forum Collection ARS.0073
Archive of Recorded Sound
New Arts Forum Collection
1972
ARS.0073
Bielawa, Herbert
1 box: 7 open reel tapes
Archive of Recorded Sound
Recorded works from American academic electronic music studios, originally submitted to the New Arts Forum series of concerts at San Francisco State University and elsewhere. The Forum was produced by Herbert Bielawa and D. Gareth Loy in 1972.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Scope and Contents
The New Arts Forum Collection consists of seven open reel tapes originally submitted to the New Arts Forum series of electronic music concerts at San Francisco State University (known at the time as San Francisco State College) and elsewhere. The Forum was produced by composer and teacher Herbert Bielawa and D. Gareth Loy in 1972. Material came from composers then active at American electronic music studios in Atlanta, SUNY-Albany, McGill, and University of Illinois, as well as SF State's own studio.
Arrangement
These recordings were used in performance. There is some possibility that tapes, reels, and boxes may have been mixed up. Aural confirmation is necessary to correctly determine contents.
Indexing Terms
New Arts Forum.; San Francisco State University.; Electronic music
- 1. Recordings
  - Atlanta Electronic Music Center, director Richard Robinson, 1972-01-10; 1 10.5" open tape reel; Mills, Harvey; Robinson, Richard Allan; Stegall, Sydney (Audio 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Ambience (1970); Formant Piece (1967) / Richard Robinson -- Herr Professor Kreidebrechen's Herzmuscheldrehen (1971); J'ai Vonie / Sydney Stegall -- Dorain Green (1971) / Harvey Mills -- Alea (1971-1972); Band 220 (1971) / Richard Robinson
  - Catholic University of America Electronic Music Laboratory, director H. Emerson Meyers, 1972-01-10; 1 10.5" open tape reel; Ecton, Richard; Gingery, Ralph; Mardirosian, Haig; Meyers, Emerson (Audio 1)
    Rhythmus (1970) / E. Meyers -- Konzept II (1972) / Haig Mardirosian -- Parameters (for flute and two-channel tape, 1971); Seneca (for percussion and two-channel tape) / Richard Ecton -- In Memoriam (for soprano and tape, 1966) / E. Meyers -- Aeimptx (for pre-recorded sounds, 1971) / Ralph Gingery -- Intervals I (1969) / E. Meyers -- Fantasia (for organ and two-channel tape, 1970) / Haig Mardirosian.
    All electronic sounds made on Moog equipment plus an alexophone and standard audio physics laboratory equipment. 3, 4, and 8 recorded with soloists in studio. 5 recorded in concert. All composers other than Professor Meyers were students at Catholic University.
  - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Experimental Music Studio, directors Herbert Brun and James Beauchamp [strong likelihood that this is McGill University Electronic Music Studio recordings, Tape 2. see note], 1972-01-27; 1 10.5" open tape reel (Audio 1)
    As noted on reel and beneath label on tape box: Fourth of July Celebration, Chambana 1969 / Phillip Musser -- Hymn 173 (1971) / Barry Brosch -- Streams and Impulses (1971) / James Beauchamp -- ! Ovarb (1971) / Phillip Musser -- Chairs / Barry Brosch -- Infraudibles / Herbert Brun.
    As noted on label taped over previous credits on tape box: McGill University Electronic Music Studio, director Paul Pederson. Tape 2. 1972-02. Cento / Istvan Anhalt -- For Margaret, Motherhood, and Mendelssohn / Paul Pedersen -- Uber Allen Gipfeln Ist Ruh... / Albert Mayr.
  - McGill University Electronic Music Studio, 1972; 1 10.5" open reel tape (Audio 1)
    sticker on tape box identifing contents is missing
  - McGill University Electronic Music Studio. Tape 1., 1972-02; 1 10.5" open tape reel; Anhalt, István (Audio 1)
    Scope and contents
    Foci / Istvan Anhalt
  - Electronic Music from San Francisco State [program was in tape box], 1972; 1 10.5" open tape reel (Audio 1)
  - State University of New York at Albany Electronic Music Studio [Chadabe letter was in tape box], 1972; 1 10.5" open tape reel; Chadabe, Joel (Audio 1)
    Rounds, a Jazz Collage (1972) / Joel Chadabe
- 2. Program and correspondence, 1 folder
  - correspondence from Joel Chadabe to Herbert Bielawa, 1972-01-27 (Text 1)
  - program for New Arts Forum Electronic Music Premiere No.8, with illustrated handbill for several events on reverse, 1972 (Text 1)